### Personal details:

Full Name: Henry Joseph Story born: 29 July 1967, England web: http://bblfish.net/email: henry.story@bblfish.net

#### Overview:

During the last 8 years as a professional software engineer, the most interesting project I worked on was the BabelFish machine translation service at AltaVista. I there gained full life cycle experience on a high profile project, as I was involved in everything from its initial architecture and design, to its deployment, testing and even PR. I was fully involved in the development of all three tiers of the service: rewriting the legacy back end application to use sockets, developing the middle tier for performance and scalability, and developing a flexible front end.

## Summary:

- Over 8 years of professional work experience as a Software Engineer
- Very strong experience in Web Applications in very high volume environment (J2EE)
- · Good Object Oriented (OO) and declarative programming knowledge
- Architectural and some management experience
- Well developed analytic skills (mathematics, logic and psychology)
- Trilingual: English, French and German
- Well organized, efficient, quick learner, team worker, successful risk taker

# Professional Experience:

[April 2003 to September 2003] SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PHILIPS, EINDHOVEN, NETHERLANDS

Contract work for Michael Bailey Associates, London.

role: ATG deployment specialist for Philips Consumer Electronics.
technology: ATG dynamo 5.1 deployment, complex Bash shell scripting, Java
servlet coding, XML parsing using JDOM, apache installation, tomcat servlet
development, CVS administration, exploring Larch version control tool.

[September 2002 to January 2003] SOFTWARE ENGINEER, VIEWGATE NETWORKS, STAINES, SURREY

product: Telecoms VPN tool development in Java. Developed business object
layer, implemented clustering algorithm, debugged database connection layer,
worked with XML messaging protocol to swing client, Perl scripting,...
technology: RMI, mySQL, jdbc, Java collections, XML, jdk1.4 logging. UML for
database structures

[April, May and June 2002] RESEARCH ASSISTANT, INSEAD, FRANCE<sup>1</sup> project: Semantic-web Ontology Editor.

description: I refactored the web application to use the Model/View/Controller design pattern using the Barracuda framework. I also introduced the team to Ant builds, JUnit testing and source control management.

technology: Barracuda framework, ant, junit, MVC, subversion

<sup>1</sup> T was talasammuting from Can Bransissa California HCR to got some more manay tagathar to nyongro

[October and November 2001] SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SYSTRAN, FRANCE<sup>2</sup> project: Single threaded Perl scripting for high volume multitasking servers using the select(..) socket call. I also experimented with a similar architecture using the Java NIO libraries in the jdkl.4. Documented libraries using the DocBook SGML format.

technology: perl, select socket call, Java NIO, DocBook, UML

[January to August 2001] SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ETRANSLATE, SAN FRANCISCO.

project: Wrote a Vignette Adapter in Java for their GlobalLink product.
 Wrote a table pagination module for the Enhydra application server.
 Helped debug the internationalisation elements of their application.
technology: MVC, Enhydra, XMLC, Vignette, Tcl-Tk, JDBC, UML

[September 1996 to December 2000] SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ALTAVISTA, PALO ALTO, CALIFORNIA.

role: Engineering lead on the BabelFish project.

project: I was responsible for the BabelFish <a href="http://babelfish.altavista.com">http://babelfish.altavista.com</a> from its baptism in late 1997, to programming, debugging and deploying the various versions of it in 2000. The service was nominated twice for the Webby Awards, and was the focus of attention of over 200 articles in the press worldwide.

It was launched as prototype running as a C CGI. The success of the prototype warranted rebuilding it in a multi-threaded environment to increase the performance, scalability and reliability of the service. After some detailed proof of concepts in Java, we selected the ATG Dynamo server.

The service was composed of three architectural layers all of which I was

The service was composed of three architectural layers, all of which I was responsible for developing. The requirements were for a very high volume server (up to 4 million translations a day) to reliably serve (24 hours a day) at AltaVista speed standards all the translation requests.

-On the back end I had to add a socket layer to the legacy single threaded translation servers. This was done in C. These servers also required careful monitoring, which was done with Perl scripts, as they tended to crash regularly (they were designed to work on mainframes of the 70ies)

-The middle tier was required to download pages efficiently, parse their content for translation and send them in a load balanced way to the translation servers.

-Finally the front end had to be flexible, yet fast, as AltaVista prided itself on its ability for near instantaneous response, and liked to change its look and feel quite regularly.

#### technology:

-back end: C, sockets in C, Perl

-middle tier: java threads, java.net.\*, java.io.\*, javacc, internationalization, Unicode, CGI

-web tier: JSP, Servlets, XML, WAP, HTML, HTTP, ATG Dynamo J2EE server, Apache, Netscape Enterprise Server, Microsoft IIS

project: Prior to that I helped write a Java applet that was deployed on the
main site. The requirements here were for minimal download time so it had to be
small (40k) The applet was tested on 40 different browsers (including Netscape
for windows 3.1)

technology: java applet, AWT

[February to August 1996] JUNIOR RESEARCHER, IMPERIAL COLLEGE, LONDON project: research with OMG on e-commerce agent protocols.

[October 1993 to February 1995] LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER FOR THE UNIVERSITY OF WESTMINSTER, LONDON, TRANSPORT STUDIES GROUP.

project: Developed a database editor and a 2D simulation of transport in Southampton for a multimedia survey on the impact new technologies could have on transport.

technology: Visual Basic, Microsoft Access, Photoshop

[April March 1992] RESEARCH ASSISTANT, WAKEHAM ASSOCIATES. project: Researched the private health market in the UK.

21 was talogomenting from Can Bransiago California HCN while woiting for H1D work normit wish

## Education

[October 1994 to October 1995] MSC IN FOUNDATIONS OF ADVANCED INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY AT IMPERIAL COLLEGE, LONDON.

My thesis was on Distributed Artificial Intelligence and Temporal Reasoning.

[October 1991 to July 1993] MPHIL IN PHILOSOPHY, BIRKBECK COLLEGE LONDON Specialized in Philosophy of Mind, Philosophy of Language and Wittgenstein. Did not finish due to lack of funds.

[June 1990] BA IN PHILOSOPHY, KING'S COLLEGE LONDON.
Specialized in Modal Logic, Philosophy of Language and Philosophy of Mind. Upper 2nd.

[Previous] A LEVELS IN MATHS (A) AND PHYSICS (B), NORWICH, ENGLAND

[Previous] BACCALAUREATE IN PHILOSOPHY/MATHS, FONTAINEBLEAU, FRANCE

## IT Skills

[Certification] Sun Certified Java Developer (92%)

[Programming Languages] Java [7 years, expert], C [1.5, good], Perl [2 years, good], Prolog [1 year, good], bash [very well versed], ...

[Java Experience:] java.net.\* [4 yrs, very good], JNI [3 months], RMI [5 months], NIO [1 month]

JDBC [ 6 months], JDO, Enterprise Java Beans [theoretical knowledge, no hands on experience]

Internationalization [3 yrs, expert]

High volume and high performance multithreaded programming [2 yrs, very good] Xerces [2 months], SAX [2 months], Javacc [2 yrs]

Servlets [4 years, expert], XMLC [6 months], Barracuda [3 months], JHTML [6 months], JSP, AWT [1 year]

[Application Servers] ATG Dynamo [12 months, especially DAS], Vignette [4 months, but no interest], Enhydra [6 months], Microsoft IIS [8 months, good], Jboss [1 month], Apache Tomcat [2 months], Apache web server [3 years], Netscape Enterprise Server [3 months]

[Databases] Mysql [5 months], Oracle [3 months], others[1 yr]

[Operating Systems] Linux [5 yrs, expert administration and user], Solaris [2 yrs, administration and end-user], Digital Unix (OSF1) [3 yrs, good], VAX-VMS, Microsoft Windows NT [2 yrs]

[Editors] Vi, Emacs, Netbeans, Rational Rose

[Software Management Tools] ClearCase [end user only], CVS [end user with some administration], Ant [good], Junit [good]

[Document Creation] StarOffice/OpenOffice, Microsoft Office, Lyx, Microsoft Office

[Document Languages] HTML, XML, LaTex, XML DocBook format

## Other Skills

[languages] French, German and English fluently.

I went through the French educational system from the age of 6 until the age of 18. I attended University in England. My mother is Austrian.

[sports] Kite Surfing, Telemark Skiing, Motorbiking, bicycling, swimming Purple in Judo for the University of London

[Strategy Games] Go: 7 kyu on kgs.kiseido.com

[Photography] exhibition in 1990 in INSEAD, France